This was the condition of Pastor Frederick when he came to The SCOAN.
He came all the way from Kenya to The SCOAN unable to walk.
You can see the expression of pain on his face as he positions himself to crawl forward.
Falling on his hands and knees, this is the only way Pastor Frederick could move by himself
when he arrived at The SCOAN.
The simple act of moving from one room to another, something that was once so easy for him to do
has become a tedious and very painful task.
Clip "Do NOT Try This At Home!!!"
You can see by the tense expression and sweat on his face just how difficult it is for him
to move from place to place without the assistance of another person.
Clip "Do NOT Try This At Home!!!"
He gradually makes his way towards the bed and with another gasp of pain and exertion
he awkwardly heaves himself up, onto the bed.
What could have made the pastor of a large ministry,
who just a week ago was energetically preaching at his pulpit now crawl on his hands and knees?
Let's hear from him.
I come from Nairobi, Kenya.
My name is Pastor Frederick.
I am a pastor and I used to pray for people.
Now I feel pain.
I can't walk.
I prayed and nothing has happened.
The name of our ministry is Word and Repentance Ministries, Nairobi, Kenya.
The reason why I came here – after preaching on Sunday, I had an attack in our church.
I had some pain in my left ankle.
I came by chance.
For now, I can't walk.
People have been helping me, to carry me but I don't want to bother them now.
I can't walk without any help.
Now I'm crawling like a baby.
From the toilet, I can't go alone.
I have to crawl like a baby.
You saw me a few minutes ago.
I could not walk alone.
I was just crawling because I don't want to bother people again to carry me.
Now I can't walk.
I feel pain.
Right now, I'm sitting down.
I want the man of God to pray for me so that I can walk.
This right ankle is painful.
You can see it's a bit swollen here.
Even now, it has come to my knee.
My knee is swollen. I can't fold it.
It is swollen.
Right now I can't walk.
I can't do anything.
I can't preach.
I'm sitting down, I'm just sleeping.
I can't do anything. I can't walk.
I'm just sleeping the whole day.
I feel a headache now.
We thank God Almighty for bringing you here to The SCOAN.
We believe with you that God Almighty will use the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, to put an end
to these problems in your life today, in Jesus' name.
Amen.
WORD AND REPENTANCE CHURCH, Nairobi, Kenya, by Pastor Fredrick Okuku
What you are watching is a footage from Pastor Frederick's church - the Word and Repentance Ministry,
in Nairobi, Kenya.
This is the Word and Repentance Ministry in Nairobi.
You are watching clips from their recording of what took place during some of their Sunday services,
led by Pastor Frederick Okuku.
Pastor Frederick regards his ministry as a deliverance ministry.
You can see how he conducts himself among the congregation
and how he interacts with different people, with different problems.
Notice how he uses physical strength, pushing, pulling, and holding the different individuals,
in an attempt to deliver them.
But the Bible says, "It is not by power or by might but by My Spirit, says the Lord".
Healing, deliverance, blessing and salvation are not brought to pass by anything done by man.
What we receive of Jesus Christ is not a mere product of any man's natural ability or power.
While man has the ability to preach, to speak and to touch on the outside, it is the Holy Spirit who heals,
saves, blesses and delivers as He wills.
Therefore, ministers of God must be under the check and conduct of the Holy Spirit at all times.
Where God guides He provides.
Where God leads, His solution, provision and protection be.
This was how the services at the Word and Repentance Ministry had been going on for some time.
But one day, Pastor Frederick met with a stiff opposition.
During the service a woman possessing 7 evil spirits came forward.
But this was not the end of the encounter.
Events which may seem ordinary can have extraordinary effects in the spirit,
much of which are hidden to the ordinary eye.
After the demons had warned Pastor Frederick to leave them alone,
when he persisted, they threatened to destroy him.
Not unlike the 7 sons of Sceva, when asked by Pastor Frederick, "Do you know me?",
the demons repeatedly replied, "No".
Demons can recognize imposters and can distinguish them from those with real spiritual power.
This is a reminder that demons are real, and Christianity is not to be practised as a hobby,
for there is danger in it.
Let's watch the encounter between Pastor Frederick and the demon-possessed woman.
Come out you sickness.
Contrary spirit, I command you, come out.
Every sickness, I command you, come out.
Look at my eyes, look there, look here.
Stop looking sideways.
Look at me.
You are going?
Yes.
Manifestation. What is making her to talk?
Who can answer me?
We are seven.
You are seven?
Yes, we are seven.
I'm telling you, we are seven.
What is she saying?
How many are you here?
We are seven.
You are not listening.
You! Don't disturb me!
You want to "pick" me?
Come!
OK, I'm coming.
No!
WORD AND REPENTANCE CHURCH - NAIROBI, KENYA
Do you know me?
No, no, no, no.
Open your eyes.
Do you know me?
No.
If you are powerful, open your eyes.
She has refused to open her eyes.
No.
Leave me alone.
WORD AND REPENTANCE CHURCH - NAIROBI, KENYA
... destroy...
We will destroy you.
WORD AND REPENTANCE CHURCH - NAIROBI, KENYA
You are the one who has been killing people.
Those who have been delivering you have been dying.
Do you want to kill me?
Come and kill me.
Deliverance Time
Kill me too.
Are you not the ones who kill pastors?
Those who tried to deliver you, you killed them.
Deliverance Time
Raise up your handkerchiefs to impact it with fire.
That night after the service, he was attacked by the evil spirits
and found himself unable to walk the next morning.
For the first time it dawned on Pastor Frederick that he was on a dangerous mission.
Immediately, Pastor Frederick set about making his way to The SCOAN
in Lagos, Nigeria, in search of a solution.
On Sunday, Pastor Frederick was assisted to the prayer line to receive prayer from Prophet T.B. Joshua.
He calls out for help.
You are now watching footage of how Pastor Frederick was aided by two men
to get to the prayer line that Sunday morning.
Not my brother but it's me, oh Lord, 'cos I'm standing in the need of prayer.
It's me...
They have come to God's presence today, to the arena of liberty to be set free.
Man of God, help me. I want to walk.
I cannot walk.
There were some agents who came to the church and said they had come to attack me.
They said they were coming to attack you in the church?
Yes.
They said they will attack me.
And they attacked you?
Yes.
Let us see how you walk.
This is a pastor from Kenya.
This is how I was going to the toilet.
It was hard for me.
Father, let Your name be glorified.
Come on, look here.
Stand up.
Just stand up.
This was the man who could not rise to his feet without someone supporting him.
About 3 to 4 people brought him here today all the way from Kenya.
Thank You, Jesus.
OK, come.
This is a pastor from Kenya.
Deliverance Time
Watch your screen and see what is happening.
Total deliverance from that severe evil attack.
Right now the man of God said, "Walk, in the name of Jesus Christ".
Thank You, Jesus.
I can now walk.
I am free. I will preach now.
Thank You, Jesus.
Can we see how he was carried here today?
Very soon we are going to watch his condition before now.
Can you come here now? Come to the seat now.
Let's watch the video.
Right now you can see the man walking by himself without any support.
Thank You, Jesus.
I am free.
I am healed. Thank You, Jesus.
Man of God, I sold the church keyboard for me to come here.
People were contributing money.
You sold the keyboard of the church to buy the ticket?
To buy the ticket because they were even fighting financially.
Here is the keyboard from Pastor Frederick's church, which he sold in order to purchase the ticket
to come to The SCOAN in Lagos.
These are the members of his congregation, who also contributed funds towards his flight ticket, so that
he could come for deliverance, having been spiritually attacked after one of his Sunday services.
They fought you financially?
I help people.
No, no, no, no. They are not fighting you.
I think your anointing is questionable.
I don't want you to say anything against the anointing of God.
Yes, sir.
OK. You begin to tell me that because you help people
- that is why they attacked you, you were attacked financially, health-wise.
Who are you? Am I not helping people?
Your calling is questionable.
Now, we have to sit down and ask God, Lord Jesus for His mercy and His favour.
You have a passion for His Word, and I know this is your desire now.
We will pray together. OK?
Yes, sir.
What you are saying now is blasphemy.
Forgive me, sir.
Ask God to forgive you.
Don't ever say that because you help people, you were attacked.
Where is Jesus then?
Is it your power?
No.
If you are attacked, they attack Jesus.
If they beat you, they beat Jesus - if you are really from Jesus.
Yes.
Clip "Do NOT Try This At Home!!!"
I am not saying you don't have a calling but there is something wrong somewhere.
So, don't complain again that you help people and that's why they attacked you.
It is blasphemy.
Thank you.
OK.
STANDARD FOR LIFE
We are not doing this for any reason but as a lesson for me, number one, and a lesson for you, number two.
Seven sons of Sceva - like I have told you...
This use of the name Jesus inspired them to try using the same name as an incantation.
When they were saying, 'In the name of Jesus, God of Paul, whom Paul called'
and satan said to them, 'We know Jesus, we know God of Paul, who are you?'
This is exactly what happened here.
You may be doing it for 2, 3, 4, 5, 7 years,
but when the repercussion comes, it will be so great that people can see that
'Look, with what you are doing in the name of Jesus - why this?'
After that, we'll now pray for our pastor and tell the pastor here, his calling.
He should not go beyond his calling.
Preach the Gospel, sing wonderful songs God has given you.
When it is time to pray, offer the prayer and leave them for their faith.
Don't call anybody and begin to perform one-on-one prayer - it is dangerous if you don't have that calling.
When it is time for deliverance, pray and call the power of God to descend on those contrary spirits.
It will happen.
Not going into their midst - it is a different anointing.
It is great going into their midst and to begin to have a personal encounter with these people.
It is the most dangerous thing.
When you have the anointing to provoke them, you can go and provoke them.
When it comes to responsibility from God, the more your faithfulness, the more your responsibility.
If your faithfulness is reducing, your responsibility will also reduce.
My pastor - this is what I want you to know.
We will pray with you, the congregation will pray with you.
We will pray for your ministry.
Your ministry will remain.
Nothing will happen to your ministry.
What happened to you is to strengthen your desire.
It's not meant to destroy your ministry.
This is the time to be closer to God so that you can hear God louder.
Before now, you heard God loud but not louder.
When you get back to Kenya, start trusting in God's authority, not majority.
The problem you people have is that you trust majority.
Be closer to God, go to the mountain, have a place to pray.
Your life must be full of prayer.
Have more devotion, more commitment, more prayer.
The first place where we have to prosper in the Church is our spiritual life.
TESTIMONY TIME
My name is Pastor Frederick Okuku.
I am from Kenya.
I really love the man of God ever since I saw his tape and I started watching him on Emmanuel TV.
I was inspired by his ministry and I really liked what he was doing.
I couldn't walk.
What happened was that after prayer, I felt a pain on my left ankle.
They decided to take me to the airport.
I arrived here, I could not walk. I was taken to the room.
It was difficult for me to walk but after the prayer - it was like a twinkle of an eye - I received my healing.
And not only that.
After the prayer, my wife called me from Kenya and told me that one of my sons could not go to the toilet,
could not pass urine, that I must help her with prayer.
I said I would not hide it from the man of God. I would tell him straight away.
She then said, "Okay".
He stretched his hand and told me to go and call her back.
Immediately, when I called her back, my wife told me that the boy was OK; he has passed urine.
After the prayer, I got healed; I'm OK.
Now, I can do anything.
Can you do those things you couldn't do before?
Hallelujah. Shall we clap for wonderful Jesus!
I want to warn men of God not to imitate because what they don't know, they speak about it
and what they know, they destroy.
This one cannot be destroyed.
That's why I came here.
I thank God for everything because my past is over.
Wait for God's time because God's time is the best time.
Stop imitating any man of God.
If God has called you, just do it the way He has called you.
God will not "certify" your calling and leave you.
He will fight until the end.
I'm also a gospel singer and I would like to sing for the Lord for what He has done for me.
I have a Father
that would never ever fail me
Jesus is my Father
Rock of ages never ever fail
I have a Father
that would never ever fail me
Jesus is my Father
He would never ever fail me
Rock of ages never ever fail
I have a Father
that would never ever fail me
Jesus is my Father
He would never ever fail me
Rock of ages never ever fail
I have a Father
that would never ever fail me
Jesus is my Father
He would never ever fail me
Rock of ages never ever fail
I have a Father
that would never ever fail me
Jesus is my Father
He would never ever fail me
Rock of ages never ever fail
I have a Father
that would never ever fail me
Jesus is my Father
He would never ever fail me
Rock of ages never ever fail
STANDARD FOR LIFE
Let us pray for our evangelist.
Before the prayer, like I have said - a lesson to everyone of us.
Don’t say, "Amen" because somebody says, "In the name of Jesus".
Say "Amen" because you believe.
Tell your neighbour, "Don't say 'Amen' because the pastor says, 'In the name of Jesus'.
Say 'Amen' because you believe.
Don't say 'Amen' because T.B. Joshua says, 'In the name of Jesus'.
Say 'Amen' because you believe".
Clip "Do NOT Try This At Home!!!"
Stretch your hand and pray for the church, pray for the evangelist.
In Jesus Christ's name, we pray!
[Amen.]
Evangelist, stand up.
Stretch your hand.
In the mighty name of Jesus Christ!
Watch your screen.
In Jesus' name!
Clip "Do NOT Try This At Home!!!"
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe, to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today
and stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances, sermons and testimonies
from The Synagogue Church Of All Nations.
Emmanuel TV – Changing lives, Changing nations and Changing the world.
TT: Robert Begier
RV: Mel Flowers 21/06/18